=Within The Grip=
=داخل القبضة=
=Episode 24=
=الحلقة 24=
(Side by Side)
(جنباً إلى جنب)
(Virtue of Heaven and Earth)
(فضيلة السماء والأرض)
(Pavilion Master's Token)
(رمز سيد الجناح)
The Xuanji Pavilion's death guards only obey the token without question.
لا يطيع حراس الموت في جناح شوانجي سوى الرمز دون أي نقاش.
If one day, the token falls into the wrong hands,
إذا وقع الرمز يوماً ما في الأيدي الخطأ،
are we supposed
هل من المفترض أن
to become the blade in their hands that slaughters the loyal and righteous?
ليصبحوا النصل في أيديهم الذي يذبح المخلصين والأبرار؟
But now, it is in your hands.
لكن الأمر الآن بين يديك.
Starting today,
ابتداءً من اليوم،
you are the Master of the Xuanji Pavilion.
أنت سيد جناح شوانجي.
- Master - Master.
- سيد - سيد.
I'm just like any of you, raised in the Pavilion.
أنا مثل أي واحد منكم، نشأت في الجناح.
I don't know who I am,
لا أعرف من أنا،
the purpose behind each task,
الهدف من كل مهمة،
or where tomorrow will take me.
أو إلى أين سيأخذني الغد.
We're just cogs spinning along a set track
نحن مجرد تروس تدور على مسار محدد
and blades in anyone's grasp.
والشفرات في متناول أي شخص.
I've asked myself countless times.
لقد سألت نفسي هذا السؤال مرات لا تحصى.
What do I truly seek?
ما الذي أسعى إليه حقاً؟
Freedom? Power?
الحرية؟ السلطة؟
No, neither.
لا، ولا هذا ولا ذاك.
I want to understand what path I walk,
أريد أن أفهم المسار الذي أسلكه،
find my own way,
أجد طريقي الخاص،
make my own choices and live for myself.
أتخذ قراراتي بنفسي وأعيش من أجلي.
Even if this path must be walked alone,
حتى لو كان لا بد من سلوك هذا الطريق بمفردي،
I hope each of you finds your own way.
أتمنى أن يجد كل واحد منكم طريقه الخاص.
You're not dead?
أنت لست ميتاً؟
Did you expect me to die in the bamboo grove outside the city
هل كنت تتوقع أن أموت في غابة الخيزران خارج المدينة؟
or at the wedding days ago?
أم في حفل الزفاف قبل أيام؟
So it was you.
إذن أنت كنت أنت.
After all these years of your care,
بعد كل هذه السنوات من رعايتك،
how should I repay it?
كيف أسدد هذا الدين؟
Pity that blades don't know mercy. Don't resist pointlessly.
يا للأسف أن السيوف لا تعرف الرحمة. لا تقاوم عبثاً.
You deceived me with two fake deaths!
لقد خدعتني بوفاتين مزيفتين!
Do you really believe
هل تصدق حقاً؟
disguises and voice changes could fool the Xuanji Pavilion?
هل يمكن للتنكر وتغيير الصوت أن يخدعا جناح شوانجي؟
For your plan,
بالنسبة لخطتك،
you even disfigured that person.
بل إنك شوهت ذلك الشخص.
Or did you think after Chief He's death,
أم أنك فكرت بعد وفاة الرئيس هي؟
no one would suspect you?
لن يشك بك أحد؟
Chief He served Father for years with utmost caution.
لقد خدم الرئيس والده لسنوات بأقصى درجات الحذر.
No one ever uncovered his close ties to your mother
لم يكشف أحد قط عن علاقته الوثيقة بوالدتك
or to the Right Chancellor...
أو إلى المستشار المحترم...
no, your grandfather.
لا، جدك.
He even destroyed the secret tunnels for the messenger hamster.
بل إنه دمر الأنفاق السرية الخاصة بالهامستر الرسول.
Pity even the tightest plan has flaws.
من المؤسف أن حتى أكثر الخطط إحكاماً لا تخلو من العيوب.
The Heaven task was issued before the hamster returned.
تم إصدار مهمة الجنة قبل عودة الهامستر.
It narrowly avoided disaster.
لقد نجا بأعجوبة من كارثة.
It's just a mouse.
إنها مجرد فأرة.
The Pavilion's Heaven tasks are highly secret.
مهام جناح الجنة سرية للغاية.
But they can't appear by magic in the Shadow Pavilion.
لكن لا يمكنهم الظهور بالسحر في جناح الظلال.
You can
أنت تستطيع
start investigating from the capital's drainage pipes.
ابدأ التحقيق من أنابيب الصرف الصحي في العاصمة.
The hamster led us through the tunnels to the Right Chancellor's mansion.
قادنا الهامستر عبر الأنفاق إلى قصر المستشار.
Whether it was Gu Wenshuang, Chief He,
سواء كان ذلك غو وينشوانغ، أو الرئيس هي،
or the Right Chancellor, they all shielded you well.
أو المستشار المحترم، لقد حموك جميعًا جيدًا.
With no evidence against you, I could only step back
لعدم وجود أي دليل ضدك، لم يكن بوسعي إلا التراجع.
in order to pull you in.
لجذبك.
The ultimate winner is still me.
الفائز النهائي ما زلت أنا.
Useless. My agents lurk near him.
لا فائدة منه. عملائي يتربصون بالقرب منه.
Fireworks signal the order.
الألعاب النارية تُعلن بدء النظام.
If you value his life, release me now.
إذا كنتم تقدرون حياته، فأطلقوا سراحي الآن.
My dear brother.
أخي العزيز.
Why do you care so deeply about his life?
لماذا تهتم كثيراً بحياته؟
You should hate him as I do.
يجب أن تكرهه كما أكرهه.
Your mother's death condemned you to years of suffering.
لقد حكمت وفاة والدتك عليك بسنوات من المعاناة.
You were sidelined for so long because of his incompetence.
لقد تم تهميشك لفترة طويلة بسبب عدم كفاءته.
If I die with him today,
إذا متُّ معه اليوم،
even if you inherit the throne,
حتى لو ورثت العرش،
how will you silence public criticism?
كيف ستُسكت الانتقادات العامة؟
You're right. I care nothing for his life.
أنت محق. لا أهتم بحياته.
Today, I can spare your life.
اليوم، أستطيع أن أنقذ حياتك.
Father failed to discipline you, but I cannot take his place.
لقد فشل أبي في تأديبك، لكنني لا أستطيع أن أحل محله.
So I'm sending you to the royal tombs to keep your mother company.
لذا سأرسلك إلى المقابر الملكية لتؤنس والدتك.
You dare?
أتجرؤ؟
Why wouldn't I dare?
لماذا لا أجرؤ؟
Take him away.
خذوه بعيداً.
I haven't lost yet.
لم أخسر بعد.
I haven't lost.
لم أخسر.
Your Highness, regarding His Majesty...
صاحب السمو، بخصوص جلالة الملك...
Some words, some things,
بعض الكلمات، بعض الأشياء،
once missed, bring endless regret.
إذا فاتتك الفرصة، ستجلب لك ندمًا لا ينتهي.
In life, what is true or false?
في الحياة، ما هو الصواب وما هو الخطأ؟
Don't wait until regret consumes you.
لا تنتظر حتى يستحوذ عليك الندم.
Your Majesty, watch out!
يا جلالة الملك، احذر!
Guards! Protect me!
أيها الحراس! احموني!
Someone help!
أرجوكم ساعدوني!
Assassin!
قاتل!
Help! Someone!
النجدة! أحد ما!
Protect His Majesty!
احموا جلالته!
Guards!
حراس!
Seize them!
اقبضوا عليهم!
Be careful!
احرص!
Watch out!
انتبه!
Don't waste your effort.
لا تضيع جهدك.
I know
أنا أعرف
my own body.
جسدي.
Before, the residual poison in my body wasn't cleared.
في السابق، لم يتم التخلص من السموم المتبقية في جسدي.
Now, I've been poisoned by a hidden weapon, and I'm done for.
الآن، لقد تسممت بسلاح خفي، وقد انتهى أمري.
You look so much like your mother.
أنتِ تشبهين والدتكِ كثيراً.
Your mother, Yun Sui,
والدتك، يون سوي،
was the best woman in the world.
كانت أفضل امرأة في العالم.
She single-handedly founded the Xuanji Pavilion.
أسست جناح شوانجي بمفردها .
- Master.
- سيد.
(From that moment on, I was smitten with her.)
(منذ تلك اللحظة، أصبحت مفتونًا بها.)
It's just a pity that she fell in love with Qin Yuheng.
من المؤسف أنها وقعت في حب تشين يوهينغ.
But Qin Yuheng married someone else for the sake of his family.
لكن تشين يوهينغ تزوج من امرأة أخرى من أجل عائلته.
After Yun Sui severed ties with him,
بعد أن قطعت يون سوي علاقتها به،
she discovered
اكتشفت
that she was already pregnant with you.
أنها كانت حاملاً بك بالفعل.
She was heartbroken.
لقد انكسر قلبها.
I wanted to make her my wife.
أردت أن أجعلها زوجتي.
I never expected that our marriage
لم أتوقع أبداً أن زواجنا
would cause Qin Yuheng to be consumed by inner demons.
سيؤدي ذلك إلى استهلاك تشين يوهينغ من قبل الشياطين الداخلية.
He became deranged
لقد أصيب بالجنون
and slaughtered his entire family.
وذبح عائلته بأكملها.
(Left Chancellor's Mansion)
(يسار قصر المستشار)
(When I arrived at his mansion,)
(عندما وصلت إلى قصره،)
(the place was a river of blood, and only he remained.)
(كان المكان نهراً من الدماء، ولم يبقَ سواه.)
It was me.
كنت أنا.
I killed him.
قتلته.
I indeed killed your father.
لقد قتلت والدك بالفعل.
Later, Lianyi had an accident after entering the palace.
وفي وقت لاحق، تعرض لياني لحادث بعد دخوله القصر.
I couldn't save her.
لم أستطع إنقاذها.
(I only managed to snatch back the child taken by the assassins.)
(لم أتمكن إلا من استعادة الطفل الذي اختطفه القتلة.)
(That child was Gu Zhaoxi.)
(كان ذلك الطفل هو غو تشاوكسي.)
At that time, Yun Sui had just given birth to you.
في ذلك الوقت، كانت يون سوي قد أنجبتك للتو.
We knew there was trouble in the palace.
كنا نعلم أن هناك مشكلة في القصر.
To protect Lianyi's child,
لحماية طفل لياني،
she reluctantly left you at the Xuanji Pavilion.
تركتك على مضض في جناح شوانجي.
Then she took Lianyi's child
ثم أخذت طفل لياني
under the guise of her own child
تحت ستار طفلها
and brought him back to our family.
وأعدناه إلى عائلتنا.
We thought about investigating in secret.
فكرنا في إجراء تحقيق سري.
But the Pavilion's secrecy rules
لكن قواعد السرية في الجناح
and the palace's blockade of information
وحصار القصر للمعلومات
caused Yun Sui, who went to investigate,
تسبب ذلك في ذهاب يون سوي للتحقيق،
to finally...
وأخيراً...
It's my fault for what happened to her.
أنا المخطئ فيما حدث لها.
(Hanzhang Hall)
(قاعة هانتشانغ)
Let what happened yesterday
دع ما حدث بالأمس جانباً
be an end to all these years.
لتكون نهاية كل هذه السنوات.
The Xuanji Pavilion has protected me well.
لقد وفر لي جناح شوانجي حماية جيدة.
I posthumously name Gu Jiang as Marquis of Yong'an.
أُعلن بعد وفاته أن غو جيانغ هو ماركيز يونغآن.
The eldest son of the Gu family may inherit the title for generations.
قد يرث الابن الأكبر لعائلة غو اللقب لأجيال.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
شكراً لك يا صاحب الجلالة.
I never expected Yin Huan to have been scheming for so many years.
لم أتوقع أبداً أن يكون يين هوان قد دبر المكائد طوال هذه السنوات.
Since he's cast aside our kinship,
بما أنه قد نبذ صلة القرابة بيننا،
I shall act as if I never had this son.
سأتصرف كما لو أنني لم أنجب هذا الابن قط.
Hand him and the Right Chancellor over to the Law Tribunal for punishment.
سلموه هو والمستشار إلى المحكمة القانونية لمعاقبتهما.
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم يا جلالة الملك.
Zhou, is there any reward you want?
تشو، هل هناك أي مكافأة تريدها؟
(Hanzhang Hall)
(قاعة هانتشانغ)
Are you sure
هل أنت متأكد
you've thought it through?
هل فكرت في الأمر جيداً؟
Yes.
نعم.
Whatever you want, I can grant it.
مهما كان ما تريد، يمكنني أن أمنحك إياه.
But I will not allow you to marry her.
لكنني لن أسمح لك بالزواج منها.
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
The matters here have come to an end.
لقد انتهت الأمور هنا.
The Xuanji Pavilion's arrangements in Jiangnan have changed.
لقد تغيرت ترتيبات جناح شوانجي في جيانغنان.
I'll go check.
سأذهب لأتأكد.
You didn't come with us to the palace. Have you already guessed?
لم تأتِ معنا إلى القصر. هل خمنت ذلك بالفعل؟
That man's identity.
هوية ذلك الرجل.
Later, Lianyi had an accident. I couldn't save her.
لاحقاً، تعرضت لياني لحادث. لم أستطع إنقاذها.
I only managed to snatch back the child taken by the assassins.
لم أتمكن إلا من استعادة الطفل الذي اختطفه القتلة.
That child was Gu Zhaoxi.
كان ذلك الطفل هو غو تشاوكسي.
Since we already know who Zhaoxi is,
بما أننا نعرف بالفعل من هو تشاوكسي،
his identity isn't hard to guess.
ليس من الصعب تخمين هويته.
Nothing can be hidden from you.
لا شيء يمكن إخفاؤه عنك.
You two planned that whole wedding scene together.
لقد خططتما معاً لمشهد الزفاف بأكمله.
You knew he wasn't dead.
كنت تعلم أنه لم يمت.
Or did you do that because he hid who he really was
أم أنك فعلت ذلك لأنه أخفى حقيقته؟
and lied to you?
وكذب عليك؟
It happened so fast. I tried to play along,
حدث ذلك بسرعة كبيرة. حاولتُ أن أساير الوضع.
using a trick dagger to fake his death.
باستخدام خنجر مزيف لتزييف موته.
But a retracting dagger wasn't enough.
لكن الخنجر القابل للسحب لم يكن كافياً.
If the wound didn't bleed, the secret would be out.
إذا لم ينزف الجرح، فسوف ينكشف السر.
So I thought of cutting my palm to create a diversion.
لذا فكرت في قطع راحة يدي لإحداث تشتيت.
But he...
لكنه...
I kept telling myself that he understood my idea.
ظللت أقول لنفسي إنه فهم فكرتي.
But I wasn't injured.
لكنني لم أُصب بأذى.
And I wasn't sure
ولم أكن متأكداً
if he pressed the gem on the dagger.
إذا ضغط على الجوهرة الموجودة على الخنجر.
Perhaps that's worry clouding your judgment.
ربما يكون ذلك قلقاً يُشوش على حكمك.
Now, everything is back on track.
الآن، كل شيء عاد إلى مساره الصحيح.
That's fine.
هذا جيّد.
Father, why must you oppose this marriage?
يا أبي، لماذا تعارض هذا الزواج؟
Back then, didn't you and Mother go against everyone to be together?
ألم تخالف أنت وأمي الجميع في ذلك الوقت لتكونا معاً؟
And you made her brother a general.
وجعلت شقيقها جنرالاً.
But in the end, I couldn't protect her.
لكن في النهاية، لم أستطع حمايتها.
If you truly want to stand against all opposition and marry her,
إذا كنت ترغب حقاً في الوقوف في وجه كل معارضة والزواج منها،
you must consider if you can protect her for a lifetime.
يجب أن تفكر فيما إذا كان بإمكانك حمايتها مدى الحياة.
But haven't you two performed the wedding ceremony?
لكن ألم تُجريا مراسم الزفاف بعد؟
Chaosheng, mind your words. That was just a stopgap.
تشاوشنغ، انتبه لكلامك. لقد كان ذلك مجرد حل مؤقت.
After all, he is the Crown Prince, and I...
فهو ولي العهد، وأنا...
Now, I'm the Marquis of Yong'an.
الآن، أنا ماركيز يونغآن.
If you want to enter the palace,
إذا كنت ترغب في دخول القصر،
I will stand as your unwavering support.
سأكون سندك الثابت.
Aren't you the one who hates getting involved in trouble?
أليس أنت من يكره التورط في المشاكل؟
You even talked of selling everything. Why did you accept the ennobling?
بل إنك تحدثت عن بيع كل شيء. لماذا قبلت التكريم؟
If you choose Jiangnan,
إذا اخترت جيانغنان،
I'll sell off
سأبيع
all the shops here and go with you.
جميع المحلات هنا، وسأذهب معك.
But if you choose to enter the palace, I will be your support forever.
لكن إذا اخترت دخول القصر، فسأكون سندك إلى الأبد.
So our days of affection
لذا أيامنا من المودة
were a "stopgap" to you?
هل كانت بمثابة "حل مؤقت" بالنسبة لك؟
Chaosheng.
تشاوشينغ.
Though unremarkable, I've still offered my support to you.
رغم أن الأمر ليس لافتاً للنظر، إلا أنني قدمت لك دعمي.
You previously promised
لقد وعدت سابقاً
that I could freely share any questions or desires with you.
أن أتمكن من مشاركة أي أسئلة أو رغبات معك بحرية.
Yes.
نعم.
There are thorny matters within my household.
توجد أمور شائكة داخل منزلي.
Might you lend your assistance?
هل يمكنك تقديم المساعدة؟
What is it?
ما هذا؟
I have a beloved,
لدي حبيبة،
but she lied and told me she was in love with my elder brother.
لكنها كذبت عليّ وقالت إنها مغرمة بأخي الأكبر.
That troubles me deeply, even robbing me of sleep.
هذا الأمر يقلقني بشدة، حتى أنه يحرمني من النوم.
Did Chaosheng tell you?
هل أخبرك تشاوشنغ بذلك؟
That day, you came just in time.
في ذلك اليوم، أتيت في الوقت المناسب تماماً.
But Gu Jiang...
لكن قو جيانغ ...
The family head felt he didn't deserve to return to his sect.
شعر رب الأسرة بأنه لا يستحق العودة إلى طائفته.
Chaosheng and I agreed to send his remains to the Tianji Sect.
اتفقنا أنا وتشاوشنغ على إرسال رفاته إلى طائفة تيانجي.
As for why I infiltrated the palace that day,
أما عن سبب تسللي إلى القصر في ذلك اليوم،
didn't you say to act in seven days?
ألم تقل أن نتصرف خلال سبعة أيام؟
When will the frost and snow return?
متى سيعود الصقيع والثلج؟
May we meet again
عسى أن نلتقي مجدداً
when spirits return.
عندما تعود الأرواح.
I told you if I left again, I'd tell you my return date.
قلت لك إن غادرت مرة أخرى، فسأخبرك بموعد عودتي.
If I journey far again, I'll tell you my return date.
إذا سافرت بعيدًا مرة أخرى،
- Great.
- رائع.
So beautiful.
جميلة جداً.
I'm truly blessed to have found someone as clever as you in this life.
أنا محظوظ حقاً لأنني وجدت شخصاً ذكياً مثلك في هذه الحياة.
Failing to spend it with you would leave me with lifelong regret.
إن عدم قضاء هذا الوقت معك سيتركني مع ندم مدى الحياة.
We still have an unfinished game in the Fufeng Pavilion.
لا تزال لدينا لعبة غير مكتملة في جناح فوفينغ.
And I haven't fully mastered the techniques you taught me.
ولم أتقن تماماً التقنيات التي علمتني إياها.
Since your family affairs concluded with the wedding,
بما أن شؤون عائلتك قد انتهت بالزفاف،
let mine begin with it.
دعني أبدأ بها.
My family is a bit complicated.
عائلتي معقدة بعض الشيء.
After the wedding, I'll tell you all of it.
سأخبركم بكل شيء بعد الزفاف .
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
I want to protect her all her life.
أريد حمايتها طوال حياتها.
But she's not someone I need to protect,
لكنها ليست شخصاً أحتاج لحمايته،
but someone strong enough to stand side by side with me.
لكن شخصًا قويًا بما يكفي ليقف جنبًا إلى جنب معي.
So, will you lend a hand?
إذن، هل ستساعدنا؟
♪Because my heart knew you at first sight♪
لأن قلبي عرفك من النظرة الأولى
♪I want to hold tight this love on the wind♪
♪أريد أن أتمسك بهذا الحب بقوة في مهب الريح♪
♪Our stolen moment passes too soon♪
♪لحظتنا المسروقة تمر سريعاً جداً♪
♪Unable to wait for this love to bloom♪
♪لا أستطيع الانتظار حتى يزهر هذا الحب♪
♪Who isn't just a passerby♪
♪من ليس مجرد عابر سبيل♪
♪And whose only one are you♪
♪ومن أنت الوحيد؟♪
♪Who broke♪
♪من كسر؟♪
♪Whose heart♪
♪قلب من♪
♪Yet find it hard to part♪
♪ومع ذلك أجد صعوبة في الفراق♪
♪Trapped in pain's shallows♪
♪محاصرون في مياه الألم الضحلة♪
♪Letting tears run wild♪
♪أترك الدموع تنهمر بغزارة♪
♪Only then realizing your hand♪
♪عندها فقط تدرك يدك♪
♪Holds my thread♪
♪يحافظ على خيطي♪
(The end)
(النهاية)
♪Willows sway in the twilight breeze♪
♪تتمايل أغصان الصفصاف في نسيم الغسق♪
♪Ancient alleys guard time's secrets♪
♪الأزقة القديمة تحرس أسرار الزمن♪
♪Bluestones bear life's imprints♪
♪الأحجار الزرقاء تحمل بصمات الحياة♪
♪Falling petals, endless longing♪
♪بتلات متساقطة، شوق لا ينتهي♪
♪Longing lingers within my heart♪
♪الشوق يتردد في قلبي♪
♪Zither strings sigh for the sorrow parting♪
♪تتنهد أوتار القيثارة على فراق الحزن♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪حكايات الماضي تسكن روحي♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪تبقى المودة خالدة، لا تُنسى♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪مخطوطات ملطخة بالحبر تستحضر الماضي♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪كل ضربة تحمل فكرة♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪الرخاء يتلاشى كالأحلام♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪حكايات الماضي تسكن روحي♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪تبقى المودة خالدة، لا تُنسى♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪مخطوطات ملطخة بالحبر تستحضر الماضي♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪كل ضربة تحمل فكرة♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪الرخاء يتلاشى كالأحلام♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪حكايات الماضي تسكن روحي♪